Benjamin Hodge Web Developer

254-768-4191 /in/benjamin-a-hodge github.com/bahodge benjamin.andrew.hodge@gmail.com

In tandem with applying my technical acumen to solve real world challenges, I strive to cultivate meaningful relationships with everyone I meet. I am driven by shear internal will to succeed and see every failure as a chance to grow. I have proven myself resourceful in my quest for knowledge and experience true satisfaction when applying newly acquired skills.

Education:

Codeup

May 2018 Certificate of Completion Full-Stack Web Developer - Java

Full Sail University

June 2017 Bachelors of Science Game Design

Technical Skills:

| HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Java | MySQL | | node.js | express.js | npm | C# | Unity3D | | Spring Framework | Git | jQuery |

Recent Projects:

Full Stack Adlister Application

March 2018

This project features a full stack application which allows users to create advertisements and list them for other users to see and interact with. Using Java servlets and a MySQL database, each ad created is persistent and unique.

Alamo City Smiles Homepage

March 2018

Static web project created for a local dental office which provides visitors with an overview of the services provided. Created using standard front end technologies like Twitter Bootstrap and jQuery for future modular design.

Movie Application

February 2018

The project focuses less on the front end design of an application to offer more functionality for the user. It uses, front end technologies as well as persistent data storage. This app also takes advantage of lightweight frameworks, RESTful services and node.js.

Professional Experience:

Target:

San Antonio, TX. Electronics Team Member October 2017 – March 2017

I was entrusted as the subject matter expert for the entirety of the Electronics department in competitive national retail environment. I expertly communicated my technical know-how on the latest tech innovations with both guests and other team members. I conveyed information clearly and concisely in order to tailor a complete solution for their individual problems.

MarketSource:

San Antonio, TX. Wireless Team Lead

November 2015 - August 2017

I handled cellular and other wireless electronics sales in a highly competitive environment. I led, trained and mentored new employees in best practices and situations encountered with different customers. I was promoted to team lead in 6 weeks due to superior performance and later was selected over 14 other to take over a failing program and raise it's standing in the district by 25% within a month.

Military Experience:

United States Army:

Ft. Hood, TX.

Infantry Fireteam Leader February 2010 – June 2014

I was the senior gunner in my infantry platoon with an expertise in using the Bradley Infantry Fighting Vehicle and other wheeled vehicles. I led three subordinates directly and was often used as one of the main trainers for our company. I worked with senior leaders to develop practical solutions to common problems in both the maintenance and operation of these tracked vehicles. Those solutions were later made into standard operating procedures for our battalion.